Travis Gottwaldt

travis@gottwaldt.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/travisgottwaldt
https://gottwaldt.com

Summary

Cyber Security Analyst with experience utilizing CrowdStrike for endpoint protection and risk assessment, building Splunk dashboards for analyzing specific security metrics, Kaseya for remote troubleshooting and managing updates, Service-Now for handing security related tickets, and KnowBe4 for phishing simulations and user awareness training. I competed in the Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition for 2 years as a firewall administrator on Palo Alto firewalls, achieving 3rd place in 2023 and 1st place in 2024 in Minnesota state, where we moved on to the regionals in Chicago and placed 5th in the region. I am motivated and dedicated to staying up to date with the latest cyber trends via webinars, conferences, and podcasts.

Work Experience

Grand Casino
Cyber Security Analyst Intern
June 2024 to Current

- Vulnerability Management and Risk Assessment of over 1000 workstations.
- Utilize Kaseya for patching, and remote connect to machines and troubleshoot issues with software updates.
- Worked with KnowBe4 consultants to implement phishing simulation campaigns and set up user awareness training.
- Respond to security related tickets via Service-Now.
- Create custom dashboards in Splunk to monitor specific security metrics.

Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition

Firewall Administrator

November 2022 to March 2024

- Responsible for firewall configuration with multiple subnets.
- Implemented port/application-based security policies.
- Identify configurations that should not be there and fix or remove them.
- Monitored traffic logs for suspicious activity.
- Documented firewall configurations, policies, and procedures.

Education

A.A.S in Cyber Security

Pine Technical and Community College, Pine City MN August 2022 – May 2024

CNC Machinist Diploma

Anoka Technical College, Anoka MN January 2016 - January 2017

Honors and Awards

- 2024 Midwest Regional Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition 5th Place
- 2024 Minnesota Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition 1st Place
- 2023 Minnesota Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition 3rd Place
- Phi Theta Kappa Honors Society

Certifications

CompTIA A+

<u>Skills</u>

- CrowdStrike
- Splunk
- KnowBe4
- Kaseya
- Service-Now
- Palo Alto
- PfSense
- Wireshark
- Python
- HTML & CSS
- Communication
- Problem Solving
- Customer Service
- MS365